I like to say I have a number of bitter
pills to swallow, but if you swallow
them, things will be a lot better in
your life. And here's one of them.
Repair is a one-way street. Everybody
gets that wrong. It's not a dialogue.
It's not, "Well, these are your issues
with me. Well, these are my issues with
you." No. You have your turn, but not
then. Take turns. So, if you have a
disgruntled partner, you are at their
service. That's the first thing to
master. Tend to your partner and bring
them back into repair with you. What
does that look like? Two things. First,
do I get it? Listen. Don't argue. Don't
rebut. Empty the well. "I'm sorry you
feel bad." That's beautiful. Compassion.
"I'm sorry you feel bad. I love you. I
don't want you to feel bad. Help me
understand. What feels bad? What's it
like for you?" And then you reflect.
"This is what I hear you say. Did I get
it?" Two, is there something I could say
or do right now that would be helpful?
What would you like? And then if it's
anything short of jumping off the
Brooklyn Bridge, give it to them. Be
generous.